Tom Green

Enfield, London, Middlesex

T: 07557531180 E: tmgree@outlook.com W: https://github.com/Tmgree

Personal Profile

I am a hard working and persevering individual as demonstrated through achieving a first class mathematics degree. I have worked with several companies while studying including both large and small financial organizations as well as in customer facing roles in the retail sector. These positions have provided me with a good grounding and understanding in the practical skills needed in these environments. I can work well in a group as well as independently, which I have shown from my time at the Garden Centre and Makers Academy. When given a task I am always motivated to ensure that it is accomplished to the best of my ability making me a reliable colleague. Finally I'm passionate about not just coding, but doing that the right way using TDD, OOP, MVC, etc. I learn quickly and I have been able to pick up new languages relatively easy.

Experience

EA Sports: Fifa Talent Scout

November 2016 -

I am currently a talent scount for EA Sports, which is the dedicated football expert with time to research, review, and edit teams and players. So I help EA determine how players and teams rate and play in the game specifically for West Ham and Barnet.

Squawka May 2016 -

Currently working at football statistics company Squawka where I have been responsible for a variety of different jobs- the main being creating an algorithm that assigns every football player with a monetary value based on their performance scores and involved a lot of work with Microsoft Excel. I have also been responsible for maintain the website http://www.fantasyleague.com/ including work with html/css and a lot of work with the SQL database. From the website you can also see that I regularly write articles both informative and entertaining and I have created images for the website using Photoshop (which I have experience with using). Finally I am part of the graphic design team creating graphics both for the website as well as the social media pages ea Instagram/Facebook and Twitter

Explore Learning

May 2016 - January 2017

I was a tutor at Explore Learning, which involves teaching children of all ages (specifically GCSE) in Mathematics and English. There is an emphasis here on creating a connection with the students and getting to know them individually to further help them learn and succeed.

Enfield Grammar School

October 2015 – November 2015

Undertook some work experience at my old secondary school's Mathematics department as a teaching assistant and occasional teacher. This involved me helping out in classes of all years including A-level classes and helped me to develop my communication skills by helping students of all years (year 7-year 13) with work and problems.

Enfield Garden Centre

July 2013 - September 2013 & July 2014 - September 2014

Summer job between University years that I undertook on two separate summer holidays, helped to develop communication skills as I was working both on the tills and on shop front, so was talking to and helping out customers directly. Also a lot of manual work including plant maintenance (i.e. watering, trimming etc.) and moving garden furniture and constructing it as well as financial work-

calculating lost money from plants thrown away.

Secor Assest Management (Internship)

Summer 2014

Worked as an intern at Secor Asset Management for a couple of months this summer (as well as working at the Garden Centre). Helped to develop my skills in Microsoft Office and specifically in Excel as did a lot of financial reports using Excel. Also helped to setup their new office, including setting up VOIP services and Internet.

Volunteer Work at local RSPCA cattery

Have volunteered a significant amount of times at the Enfield RSPCA cattery, initially for my Duke of Edinburgh award. Work included playing with the cats and feeding them to make sure they were used to human exposure before they're adopted as well as talking with potential adopters and showing them the cats.

Education

University of Essex-BSc Mathematics 1st Class Degree

2012-2015

Achieved a 1st Class Degree that included a distinction in my First year as well as a first with Dean's excellence in the second. Some modules I completed include; Graph Theory, Cryptography and Codes, Statistics I & II, Vector Calculus, Complex Variables, Ordinary Differential equations, Mathematical Biology, Laws of Physics etc. My dissertation was on solving linear equations of the third degree and higher and is available to read here; http://tinyurl.com/jjt5bfj.

Enfield Grammar School 2005-2012

3 A-Levels (340 UCAS Points) - Mathematics: A*, Economics: B, Media Studies: B AS Levels in Further Mathematics and ICT 11 GCSEs all at A and B grades

Makers Academy (Coding School)

October 2015-February 2016

A very intense coding course that helped me to develop and extended my coding skills using the correct practices (like Agile methodologies that is heavily focused on Test Driven Development and Object Oriented Programing) and by writing clean and easily maintainable code. The course concentrates extensively on teamwork and pair programming but also encourages solo work, so I have experience and am very happy to code within a pair or a team.

Skills

I have excellent numeracy and mathematical skills, which I have demonstrated both in my first class Mathematics degree but also in my ability to tutor others up to A level standard. I am also very proficient with a computer and more specifically with programing as I have now been programming for a while specifically using Ruby, Javascript, Matlab and R. This also goes hand in hand with my very capable problem solving skills, both in mathematics and programming I am often faced with a series of challenging and different problems. I am a very logical person and have had a lot of experience and practice with problem solving which has made me very confident in my abilities to tackle any challenge that is thrown my way. Finally a portfolio of my programming projects can be found on my Github page and take a look at my Github CV (https://github.com/Tmgree/CV) for a better look at my programing skills. Of course I am still a junior developer and so I still have much to learn but I have demonstrated that I am able to learn very quickly and I am very eager to develop my programming

Ruby	
Javascript	0000000000
Matlab & Maplesoft	000000000
Wolfram Mathematica	000000000
SQL	0000000000
HTML & CSS	000000000
R	000000000
Photoshop	000000000